Rare Pamphlet Collection 6034
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Box: 10, Folder: 9, Publication (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Night riders in Gallup, 1935; Publication (Box 10, Folder 9)
    Author: Louis Colman
  - Item 2: Lawrence Simpson's 'Treason, 1926; Publication (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Box: 10, Folder: 10, Publication (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: The cause of industrial unrest, 1915; Publication (Box 10, Folder 10)
    Author: Amos Pinchot
    Notes: Testimony of Amos Pinchot before Commission on industrial relations, at New York city, on January 30 and February 1, 1915.
- Box: 10, Folder: 11, Publication (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: The case against waterfront screening, 1956; Publication (Box 10, Folder 11)
    Author: Committee Against Waterfront Screening
- Box: 10, Folder: 12, Publication (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: The crisis in the Socialist Party, 1933; Publication (Box 10, Folder 12)
    Author: Committee for the Preservation of the Socialist Party
- Box: 10, Folder: 13, Publication (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: War, labor and peace, 1918; Publication (Box 10, Folder 13)
    Author: Woodrow Wilson
- Box: 10, Folder: 14, Publication (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: Defend America by aiding the allies, 1940; Publication (Box 10, Folder 14)
    Author: Committee to Defend America by Aiding the Allies
- Box: 10, Folder: 15, Publication (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: Captives of Capitalism, Publication (Box 10, Folder 15)
    Author: Committee for International Workers Aid
- Box: 10, Folder: 16, Publication (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Item 1: Tampa: tar and terror, 1935; Publication (Box 10, Folder 16)
    Author: Committee for the Defense of Civil Rights in Tampa.
  - Item 2: Terror in Tampa, 1937; Publication (Box 10, Folder 16)
    Author: Committee for the Defense of Civil Rights in Tampa
- Box: 10, Folder: 17, Publication (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Item 1: Lizzie likes her job, 1920; Publication (Box 10, Folder 17)
    Author: John R. Commons
  - Item 2: Wage theories and wage policies, Publication (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Item 3: Karl Marx and Samuel Gompers, 1926; Publication (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Item 4: American shoemakers, 1648-1895, 1909; Publication (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Box: 10, Folder: 18, Publication (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Item 1: The American economic review, 1927; Publication (Box 10, Folder 18)
    Author: American Economic Association
    Notes: v.17, no.1 (1927)
  - Item 2: John R. Commons, 1930; Publication (Box 10, Folder 18)
    Author: Hermann Kroner
    Language: German.
  - Item 3: Farm prices and the value of gold, 1928; Publication (Box 10, Folder 18)
    Author: John Rogers Commons
  - Item 4: Institutional economics, 1934; Publication (Box 10, Folder 18)
- Box: 10, Folder: 19, Publication (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Item 1: The Commonwealth labor hymnal, 1940; Publication (Box 10, Folder 19)
    Author: Commonwealth College
- Box: 10, Folder: 20, Publication (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Item 1: A communication to the Hon. William Howard Taft, President of the United States, urging the creation of a federal commission on industrial relations., 1911; Publication (Box 10, Folder 20)
- Box: 10, Folder: 21, Publication (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Item 1: Communists in the textile strike, 1934; Publication (Box 10, Folder 21)
    Author: Clarence Albert Hathaway; Alex Bittelman
- Box: 10, Folder: 22, Publication (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Item 1: Program of the Communist International, together with its constitution., 1929; Publication (Box 10, Folder 22)
    Author: Communist International
  - Item 2: All-Russian Union of Art Workers, All-Russian Union of Educational Workers, 1920; Publication (Box 10, Folder 22)
- Box: 10, Folder: 23, Publication (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Item 1: United we stand: 100 years of struggle in the docks, 1956; Publication (Box 10, Folder 23)
- Box: 11, Folder: 1, Publication (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: The La Follette Third Party: will it unite or split the Progressives Forces?, 1938; Publication (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Author: Communist Party of the United States of America
  - Item 2: Who are the Communists?, Publication (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Item 3: Theses and statutes of the third (Communist) International, 1920; Publication (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Notes: Adopted by the second congress July 17th-August 7th, 1920
  - Item 4: Acceptance speeches: Communist candidates in the presidential elections., 1936; Publication (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Item 5: The American way to jobs, peace, democracy., 1954; Publication (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Box: 11, Folder: 2, Publication (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: The fight for labor's rights: election program of the Communist Party of New York, 1935; Publication (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Box: 11, Folder: 3, Publication (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Trade unions forward, 1939; Publication (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Author: Communist Party of Great Britain.
  - Item 2: Defend trade union rights: A Communist call to every trade unionist, 1949; Publication (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Item 3: Russia to-day: a survey of facts and figures, to all British trade unionists, 1941; Publication (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Item 4: A wage based on human needs for all workers in the metal engineering, ship-building and allied trades, 1946; Publication (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Author: Reg Birch
  - Item 5: Marxism & industrial workers, 1941; Publication (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Item 6: Trade union policy in the war against fascism, 1942; Publication (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Item 7: Trade unions and the war, 1940; Publication (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Item 8: Towards a greater trade union movement, 1944; Publication (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Box: 11, Folder: 4, Publication (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Party organizer, 1933; Publication (Box 11, Folder 4)
    Notes: vol.65 no. 8-9, August-September 1933.
  - Item 2: An appeal by the Central Executive Committee of the Communist International to the I.W.W., 1920; Publication (Box 11, Folder 4)
    Author: Communist Party of America
- Box: 11, Folder: 5, Publication (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: For unity of the world Communist movement, 1934; Publication (Box 11, Folder 5)
    Author: Communist Party of the U.S.A. (Opposition)
  - Item 2: The constitution and by-laws of the Communist party of the United States of America, 1938; Publication (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Item 3: Unemployment relief and social insurance, 1931; Publication (Box 11, Folder 5)
    Author: Communist Party of the U.S.A.
  - Item 4: The NRA and American labor, 1933; Publication (Box 11, Folder 5)
    Author: Will Herberg
- Box: 11, Folder: 6, Publication (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Let's look at ourselves; a brief guide for conducting a community audit., 1948; Publication (Box 11, Folder 6)
    Author: National Citizens' Council on Civil Rights
- Box: 11, Folder: 7, Publication (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Address by Louis K. Comstock, 1932; Publication (Box 11, Folder 7)
    Author: Louis K. Comstock
    Notes: At the second Annual Meeting of the Electrical Guild of North America at the Carlton Hotel, Washington, D.C.: May 19, 1932.
  - Item 2: Proposed system of wage adjustments, 1918; Publication (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Box: 11, Folder: 8, Publication (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Condiciones del trabajo femenino, 1936; Publication (Box 11, Folder 8)
    Author: Paulina Luisi
    Language: Spanish.
- Box: 11, Folder: 9, Publication (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: How the rubber workers won, 1936; Publication (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Item 2: The case for industrial organization, 1936; Publication (Box 11, Folder 9)
    Author: American Federation of Labor
  - Item 3: Industrial unions mean unity: our answer to president Green, 1936; Publication (Box 11, Folder 9)
    Author: Committee for Industrial Organization
  - Item 4: The CIO case for substantial pay increases, 1945; Publication (Box 11, Folder 9)
    Author: Philip Murray
- Box: 11, Folder: 10, Publication (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: The Faked contract, 1937; Publication (Box 11, Folder 10)
    Author: Constitutional Educational League
- Box: 11, Folder: 11, Publication (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Consumers' cooperative societies in New York State, 1922; Publication (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Box: 11, Folder: 12, Publication (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: Worker's education in the U.S. zone of Germany, 1947; Publication (Box 11, Folder 12)
    Author: Alice Hanson Cook
  - Item 2: Proposal for a project to study: trade unions and women in five European countries, 1976; Publication (Box 11, Folder 12)
    Author: Alice Hanson Cook; Val R. Lorwin; Roberta Till Retz
- Box: 11, Folder: 13, Publication (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: Mond's manacles. The destruction of trade unionism. Being the sequel to "Mond Moonshine"., Publication (Box 11, Folder 13)
    Author: A. J. Cook; A. Horner
  - Item 2: The Nine days, 1926; Publication (Box 11, Folder 13)
    Author: A. J. Cook
- Box: 11, Folder: 14, Publication (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: An all-American basis for industry, 1919; Publication (Box 11, Folder 14)
    Author: Morris Llewellyn Cooke
- Box: 11, Folder: 15, Publication (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: How to make productive co-operation a success, 1878; Publication (Box 11, Folder 15)
    Author: Alfred Smith
    Notes: Read by Alfred Smith at the Yorkshire Conference, held at Leeds, on Saturday, June 29th, 1878.
- Box: 12, Folder: 1, Publication (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: American commission for the study of the application of the cooperative system to agricultural production, distribution, and finances in European countries., 1913; Publication (Box 12, Folder 1)
    Author: Southern Commercial Congress
- Box: 12, Folder: 2, Publication (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Some American problems in 1945 and suggested solutions, Publication (Box 12, Folder 2)
    Author: People's Lobby, Inc.
    Notes: Excerpts from talks at conference of People's Lobby, Inc., Washington, D.C., January 27, 1945.
- Box: 12, Folder: 3, Publication (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Enlightenment and the world crisis, 1952; Publication (Box 12, Folder 3)
    Author: George Cosson
- Box: 12, Folder: 4, Publication (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Annotated Code of fair competition for the cotton garment industry, 1933; Publication (Box 12, Folder 4)
    Author: United States. National Recovery Administration
    Notes: As approved on Nov. 17, 1933 by President Franklin D. Roosevelt, effective November 27, 1933.
- Box: 12, Folder: 5, Publication (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Public opinion in the U.S. on foreign trade, 1946; Publication (Box 12, Folder 5)
    Author: John Lee Coulter
- Box: 12, Folder: 6, Publication (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Equal pay and the family, 1918; Publication (Box 12, Folder 6)
    Author: Kathleen Courtney
- Box: 12, Folder: 7, Publication (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Three cents an hour, 1936; Publication (Box 12, Folder 7)
    Author: Pennsylvania. Bureau of Women and Children
    Notes: An intimate picture of industrial home work in Pennsylvania, by Myrl Cowdrick, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania, 1936
- Box: 12, Folder: 8, Publication (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: The high cost of living: how to bring it down, 1937; Publication (Box 12, Folder 8)
    Author: Margaret Cowl
- Box: 12, Folder: 9, Publication (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: A short introduction to consumers' co-operation, 1936; Publication (Box 12, Folder 9)
    Author: Ellis Cowling
- Box: 12, Folder: 10, Publication (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: Present trends in the clerical occupations, 1928; Publication (Box 12, Folder 10)
    Author: Grace Longwell Coyle
- Box: 12, Folder: 11, Publication (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Craft unionism or industrial unionism: which?: a contribution to the problem of working-class economic organisation., 1922; Publication (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Box: 12, Folder: 12, Publication (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: Outlines of the history of the modern British working-class movement, 1916; Publication (Box 12, Folder 12)
    Author: William White Craik
- Box: 12, Folder: 13, Publication (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: Cigar makers: after the lay-off: a case study of the effects of mechanization on employment of hand cigar makers, 1937; Publication (Box 12, Folder 13)
    Author: Daniel Barnett Creamer; Gladys V. Swackhamer
- Box: 12, Folder: 14, Publication (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: Can socialism come by constitutional methods?, Publication (Box 12, Folder 14)
    Author: Richard Stafford Cripps
- Box: 12, Folder: 15, Publication (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: Trade unionists: report on Poland, 1946; Publication (Box 12, Folder 15)
    Author: F. A Crone; Harry Knight
- Box: 12, Folder: 16, Publication (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Item 1: An Englishman looks at American labour, 1949; Publication (Box 12, Folder 16)
    Author: R. H. S. Crossman
  - Item 2: Socialism and the new despotism, 1956; Publication (Box 12, Folder 16)
- Box: 12, Folder: 17, Publication (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Item 1: True freedom for negro and white labor, 1936; Publication (Box 12, Folder 17)
    Author: Frank Rudolph Crosswaith; Alfred Baker Lewis; Norman Thomas
  - Item 2: Negro and white labor unite for true freedom, 1942; Publication (Box 12, Folder 17)
    Author: Frank Rudolph Crosswaith; Alfred Baker Lewis
- Box: 12, Folder: 18, Publication (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Item 1: The end of the Ford myth, 1932; Publication (Box 12, Folder 18)
    Author: Robert Lunan Cruden
- Box: 12, Folder: 19, Publication (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Item 1: Henry Ford: why I favor five days work with six days pay, 1926; Publication (Box 12, Folder 19)
    Author: Henry Ford; Samuel Crowther
- Box: 13, Folder: 1, Publication (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Pork chops and politics, 1943; Publication (Box 13, Folder 1)
    Author: Joseph Edwin Curran
  - Item 2: The N. M. U. forges ahead; a report on the status of the Natinal maritime union of America, 1940; Publication (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Box: 13, Folder: 2, Publication (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Italy: victory through revolution!, 1943; Publication (Box 13, Folder 2)
    Author: Roy Curtis; Angelica Balabanoff
- Box: 13, Folder: 3, Publication (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: The political and social significance of recent labor legislation, 1914; Publication (Box 13, Folder 3)
    Author: Marshall Henry Cushing
    Notes: Address by Mr. Marshall Cushing before the National Founders' Association at the Hotel Astor, New York, Nov. 18, 1914.
- Box: 13, Folder: 4, Publication (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Red cartoons from the Daily worker, 1926; Publication (Box 13, Folder 4)
    Author: Daily worker (Chicago, Ill.)
- Box: 13, Folder: 5, Publication (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Victory Decision of the United States Supreme Court in the case of Angelo Herndon, 1937; Publication (Box 13, Folder 5)
    Notes: April, 1937. Full text of the majority decision setting aside the verdict in the Herndon case by Roberts; with the dissenting opinion of the minority by Van Devanter. With an introd. by A. Damon.
- Box: 13, Folder: 6, Publication (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Death pits in India: Report of the Indian T.U.C. to the Miners International, 1945; Publication (Box 13, Folder 6)
    Author: Shripad Amrit Dange
- Box: 13, Folder: 7, Publication (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: The battle for production, 1942; Publication (Box 13, Folder 7)
    Author: Samuel Darcy
  - Item 2: The challenge of youth: why every young worker should join the Young Workers Communist League, 1926; Publication (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Box: 13, Folder: 8, Publication (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: The open shop, 1909; Publication (Box 13, Folder 8)
    Author: Clarence Darrow
  - Item 2: The open shop, Publication (Box 13, Folder 8)
    Notes: Undated
  - Item 3: The open shop, 1904; Publication (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Item 4: Crime and criminals, 1910; Publication (Box 13, Folder 8)
    Notes: Address delivered to the prisoners in the Chicago county jail
- Box: 13, Folder: 9, Publication (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: The revolutionary movement in Spain, 1934; Publication (Box 13, Folder 9)
    Author: Helmut Rudiger
- Box: 13, Folder: 10, Publication (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: American cooperatives: yesterday--today--tomorrow, 1946; Publication (Box 13, Folder 10)
    Author: John Daniels
- Box: 13, Folder: 11, Publication (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Labor under the NRA, 1934; Publication (Box 13, Folder 11)
    Author: Carroll R. Daugherty
- Box: 13, Folder: 12, Publication (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: What means this strike?, 1913; Publication (Box 13, Folder 12)
    Author: Daniel De Leon
  - Item 2: The burning question of trades unionism, 1904; Publication (Box 13, Folder 12)
    Notes: Lecture delivered at Newark, N.J., April 21, 1904
  - Item 3: Socialism versus anarchism, 1921; Publication (Box 13, Folder 12)
    Notes: Lecture delivered at Boston, October 13, 1901
  - Item 4: Socialist reconstruction of society: the industrial vote, 1932; Publication (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Item 5: Industrial unionism, 1918; Publication (Box 13, Folder 12)
    Author: Eugene V. Debs
    Notes: Address delivered at Grand Central palace, New York, Sunday, December 10, 1905
- Box: 13, Folder: 13, Publication (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: The Negro workers, 1923; Publication (Box 13, Folder 13)
    Notes: Address delivered Tuesday, October 30, 1923, at Commonwealth Casino, 135th Street and Madison Avenue, New York City
  - Item 2: Revolutionary unionism, 1905; Publication (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Item 3: Unionism and socialism: a plea for both, 1904; Publication (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Item 4: Unionism and socialism: a plea for both, 1904; Publication (Box 13, Folder 13)
- Box: 14, Folder: 1, Publication (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: American labour: the story of the American trade union movement, 1943; Publication (Box 14, Folder 1)
    Author: Ernest Davies; Harold J. Laski
- Box: 14, Folder: 2, Publication (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: The Negro people and the Communist Party, 1943; Publication (Box 14, Folder 2)
    Author: Benjamin J. Davis
- Box: 14, Folder: 3, Publication (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Let us build a national Negro congress, 1935; Publication (Box 14, Folder 3)
    Author: John P. Davis
- Box: 14, Folder: 4, Publication (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Principles of industrial unionism, 1905; Publication (Box 14, Folder 4)
    Notes: The preamble of the Industrial Workers of the World: address delivered at Union Temple, Minneapolis, Minnesota, July 10th, 1905
  - Item 2: Marx on Mallock, or Facts vs. fiction, 1919; Publication (Box 14, Folder 4)
    Notes: Address delivered in Maennerchor Hall, New York, Tuesday, January 21, 1908, under the auspices of Section New York, Socialist Labor Party
  - Item 3: Marx on Mallock, or Facts vs. fiction, 1925; Publication (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Item 4: A decadent Jeffersonian on the socialist gridiron, 1935; Publication (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Item 5: Industrial Unionism, 1935; Publication (Box 14, Folder 4)
    Notes: Also An Address on the Same Subject Delivered at Grand Central Palace, New York, Sunday, Dec. 10, 1905, by Eugene V. Debs.
  - Item 6: Woman's suffrage, 1935; Publication (Box 14, Folder 4)
    Notes: The ballot and the class struggle
  - Item 7: Socialism vs. 'individualism', 1942; Publication (Box 14, Folder 4)
    Author: Daniel De Leon; Thomas F. Carmody
    Notes: Debate, Daniel De Leon vs. Thomas F. Carmody, Troy, N. Y., April l4, 1912.
- Box: 14, Folder: 5, Publication (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Full employment for labor and capital, 1943; Publication (Box 14, Folder 5)
    Author: R. J. Deachman
- Box: 14, Folder: 6, Publication (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Debate, which road for American workers, socialist or communist?, 1936; Publication (Box 14, Folder 6)
    Author: Norman Thomas; Earl Browder
    Notes: Norman Thomas vs Earl Browder, Madison Square Garden, New York, November 27, 1935.
- Box: 14, Folder: 7, Publication (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: A debate on the tactics of the S. T. & L. A. toward trade unions, 1900; Publication (Box 14, Folder 7)
    Notes: Debate between Daniel DeLeon of the Socialist Labor Party and Job Harriman of the Social Democratic Party, held at New Haven, Conn., November 25, 1900.
- Box: 14, Folder: 8, Publication (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Building our fences in Latin America, 1941; Publication (Box 14, Folder 8)
    Author: J. Anton De Haas
- Box: 14, Folder: 9, Publication (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Eugene Dennis indicts the Wall Street conspirators, 1948; Publication (Box 14, Folder 9)
    Author: Eugene Dennis
  - Item 2: The MacArthur ouster: a letter to members of the Communist Party, 1951; Publication (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Item 3: The fascist danger and how to combat it, 1948; Publication (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Item 4: What America faces: the new war danger and the struggle for peace, democracy and economic security, 1946; Publication (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Item 5: 21 questions about war and peace, 1950; Publication (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Item 6: Is communism unamerican?: nine questions about the Communist Party answered, 1947; Publication (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Item 7: The red-baiters menace America, 1946; Publication (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Item 8: In defense of your freedom, 1949; Publication (Box 14, Folder 9)
    Notes: Summation in the trial of the eleven communist leaders
  - Item 9: America at the crossroads: postwar problems and communist policy, 1945; Publication (Box 14, Folder 9)
    Author: Eugene Dennis; William Z. Foster
  - Item 10: The third party and the 1948 elections, Publication (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Item 11: The communists take a new look, 1956; Publication (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Item 12: Peace or war: the people against the warmakers!, 1946; Publication (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Box: 14, Folder: 10, Publication (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: The pacifist in wartime, 1942; Publication (Box 14, Folder 10)
    Author: Dorothy Detzer
- Box: 14, Folder: 11, Publication (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: The civil war in Austria; a first-hand account from eye-witnesses and participants, 1934; Publication (Box 14, Folder 11)
    Author: Julius Deutsch; David P. Berenberg
- Box: 14, Folder: 12, Publication (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: Thomas E. Dewey: Labor's candidate for district attorney, New York County., 1937; Publication (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Item 2: Truth is on the march, 1937; Publication (Box 14, Folder 12)
    Author: John Dewey
    Notes: Report and remarks on the Trotsky hearings in Mexico.
  - Item 3: Morals in politics: a collection of essays, 1945; Publication (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Item 4: Education and the social order, 1949; Publication (Box 14, Folder 12)
- Box: 14, Folder: 13, Publication (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: Petrillo's case: new light on an age-old problem: man vs. machine, 1948; Publication (Box 14, Folder 13)
    Author: Milton Diamond
- Box: 14, Folder: 14, Publication (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: Working class unity: bulwark against fascism, 1935; Publication (Box 14, Folder 14)
    Author: Georgi Dimitrov
  - Item 2: The struggle against the imperialist war, 1940; Publication (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Item 3: The united front against fascism, 1935; Publication (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Item 4: The War and the working class of the Capitalist Countries, Publication (Box 14, Folder 14)
- Box: 14, Folder: 15, Publication (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: American labor: its necessities and prospects, 1852; Publication (Box 14, Folder 15)
    Author: James Dixon
    Notes: Address of the Hon. James Dixon .. delivered before the American Institute .. Oct. 2, 1852.
- Box: 14, Folder: 16, Publication (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Item 1: How Soviet trade unions work, 1941; Publication (Box 14, Folder 16)
    Author: Maurice Dobb; J. H. Potts